{
	"config": {
		"tags":[
			"pokemon",
			"nintendo",
			"sony",
			"microsoft",
			"retro",
			"blizzard",
			"mmorpg",
			"overwatch"
		]
	},
	"multipleChoiceAnswers": {
		"characters": [
			"Mario",
			"Yoshi",
			"Bowser",
			"Toad",
			"Luigi",
			"Daisy",
			"Wario",
			"Waluigi",
			"Rosalina",
			"Birdo",
			"Baby Mario",
			"Zelda",
			"Link",
			"Ganon",
			"Navi",
			"Epona",
			"Donkey Kong",
			"Diddy Kong",
			"Sub-Zero",
			"Shao Kahn",
			"Johnny Cage",
			"Yoshimitsu",
			"Astaroth",
			"Master Chief",
			"Cortana",
			"Marth",
			"Lara Croft",
			"Samus Aran",
			"Big Boss",
			"Kratos",
			"Solid Snake",
			"Nathan Drake",
			"Gordon Freeman",
			"Cloud Strife",
			"Jim Raynor",
			"Tassadar",
			"Zeratul",
			"Sarah Kerrigan",
			"Tom Nook",
			"Little Mac"
		],
		"villains": [
			"Laughing Octopus",
			"Night Fright",
			"The Fear",
			"Bowser",
			"Wario",
			"Ganon",
			"Big Boss"
		],
		"pokemon": [
			"Eevee",
			"Pikachu",
			"Meowth",
			"Bulbasaur",
			"Growlith",
			"Magikarp",
			"Garbador",
			"Charizard",
			"Sylveon",
			"Mew",
			"Mewtwo",
			"Gyarados",
			"Dragonite",
			"Snorlax",
			"Gengar",
			"Crobat",
			"Electrode",
			"Blastoise",
			"Lucario",
			"Vaporeon",
			"Cubone",
			"Venusaur",
			"Ditto",
			"Dewgong"
		],
		"years": [
			"1945",
			"1950",
			"1953",
			"1957",
			"1960",
			"1961",
			"1964",
			"1969",
			"1970",
			"1972",
			"1975",
			"1979",
			"1980",
			"1985",
			"1986",
			"1988",
			"1990",
			"1991",
			"1994",
			"1996",
			"1999",
			"2000",
			"2004",
			"2005",
			"2009",
			"2010",
			"2011",
			"2014",
			"2019"
		],
		"retro_games": [
			"Mario Bros",
			"Tetris",
			"Asteroids",
			"Zelda",
			"Metroid",
			"Ice Climbers",
			"Missile Command",
			"Pac-Man",
			"Duck Hunt",
			"Defender",
			"Moon Lander",
			"Space Invaders",
			"Galaga",
			"Street Fighter",
			"Mega Man",
			"Contra",
			"Sonic",
			"Mario Kart",
			"Frogger",
			"Pong",
			"Chrono Trigger",
			"Final Fantasy",
			"Golden Axe",
			"Gauntlet",
			"Secret of Mana",
			"DOOM"
		],
		"games": [
			"Archeage",
			"Apex Legends",
			"Call of Duty: Modern Warfare",
			"Chrono Trigger",
			"Counterstrike",
			"Dota 2",
			"Dwarven Fortress",
			"Donkey Kong",
			"Destiny 2",
			"DOOM",
			"Diablo",
			"Dota Underlords",
			"Dauntless",
			"Excite Bike",
			"Final Fantasy VII",
			"Final Fantasy VII",
			"Final Fantasy XV",
			"Fortnite",
			"Fallout 3",
			"Gauntlet Legends",
			"Goldeneye",
			"Golf With Your Friends",
			"Guild Wars",
			"Halo 3",
			"Ikaruga",
			"Legend of Mana",
			"League of Legends",
			"Metroid Prime",
			"Mario Kart 8",
			"Mega Man X8",
			"Mortal Kombat 3",
			"Minecraft",
			"Mario Kart",
			"Overwatch",
			"Pokemon Blue",
			"Risk of Rain",
			"Runescape",
			"Super Mario Bros",
			"Street Fighter",
			"Starcraft",
			"Tetris",
			"TMNT: Turtles in Time",
			"Tabletop Simulator",
			"The Last of Us",
			"Warcraft",
			"World of Warcraft",
			"Warframe",
			"Yoshi's Island",
			"Zelda: Ocarina of Time"
		],
		"factions": [
			"Flood",
			"Hoard",
			"Alliance",
			"Covenant",
			"Ecumene",
			"Eridanus Rebels",
			"Vex",
			"Cabal",
			"Fallen",
			"Hive",
			"Taken",
			"Geth",
			"Asari",
			"Orcs",
			"Humans",
			"Elves",
			"Dwarves",
			"Undead",
			"Terran",
			"Zerg",
			"Protoss"
		],
		"consoles": [
			"NES",
			"SNES",
			"N64",
			"Gamecube",
			"Virtual Boy",
			"Wii",
			"Wii U",
			"Switch",
			"Gameboy",
			"Gameboy Advance",
			"Gameboy Color",
			"Nintendo DS",
			"3DS",
			"Dreamcast",
			"Sega Saturn",
			"32x"
		],
		"console_companies": [
			"Nintendo",
			"Sega",
			"Sony",
			"Microsoft",
			"Atari"
		],
		"gaming_companies": [
			"Blizzard Entertainment",
			"Square Enix",
			"Bethesda",
			"Obsidian",
			"Microsoft",
			"Sony",
			"Epic Games",
			"Valve",
			"Obsidian Entertainment",
			"Double Fine Productions",
			"Midway",
			"Acclaim"
		]
	},
	"questions": [
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "When was the first video game invented?",
			"answer": "1964",
			"explaination": "In October 1958, Physicist William Higinbotham created what is thought to be the first video game. It was a very simple tennis game, similar to the classic 1970s video game Pong.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"difficulty": 3,
			"choice_type": "years",
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "tf",
			"question": "Pong was the first video game ever created.",
			"answer": "False",
			"explaination": "The first video game was created in 1958 by Physicist William Higinbotham",
			"choices": [
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What year was N64 release in the United States and Japan?",
			"answer": "1996",
			"explaination": "Named for its 64-bit central processing unit, it was released in June 1996 in Japan, September 1996 in North America and Brazil, March 1997 in Europe and Australia, and September 1997 in France.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"difficulty": 3,
			"choice_type": "years",
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Pauline, the mayor of New Donk City who performs “Jump Up, Super Star” in Super Mario Odyssey, made her debut in what classic video game?",
			"answer": "Donkey Kong",
			"choices": [
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"choice_type": "retro_games",
			"author": "dandyhighwayman84",
			"tags": [
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What name did Pacman originally go by?",
			"answer": "Puckman",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Fatman",
				"Dotman",
				"Faceman"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "missymousey",
			"tags": [
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Who is __NOT__ one of the Nine Divines in the elder scrolls franchise?",
			"answer": "A and D",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Arkay",
				"Magnus",
				"Talos",
				"Nocturnal"
			],
			"difficulty": 3,
			"randomize": false,
			"author": "Renegade"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "In the Dishonored franchise what are the infected citizens called?",
			"answer": "Weepers",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Cryers",
				"Pukers",
				"Tallboys"
			],
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Renegade"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What franchise recently dethroned Tetris as the best selling franchise of all time?",
			"answer": "Minecraft",
			"explaination": "As of May 2019 Minecraft has dethroned Tetris as the best selling video game franchise of all time. Tetris games have sold 170,000,000 copies and Minecraft has sold 176,000,000 copies. Note: Tetris numbers are outdated and it's possible that Tetris is still the best-selling game but no such information exists to support this.",
			"choices": [
				"Call of Duty",
				"Grand Theft Auto",
				"Warcraft"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "In Bioware's Destiny franchise which of these is not an enemy faction?",
			"answer": "The Geth",
			"explaination": "The geth are a cybernetic hivemind made by the Quarens in the Mass Effect franchise closely related to the vex that are a cybernetic hivemind that have no known origin.",
			"choices": [
				"The Cabal",
				"The Vex",
				"The Fallen"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Renegade"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What color Yoshi was _not_ available in Super Mario World?",
			"answer": "None of the Above",
			"explaination": "In Super Mario World you could raise a baby Blue, Red, or Yellow Yoshi into an adult. You also had the standard Green Yoshi during most of the game.",
			"choices": [
				"Green Yoshi",
				"Blue Yoshi",
				"Red Yoshi",
				"Yellow Yoshi"
			],
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "tf",
			"question": "Super Mario World was a launch title for the Super Nintendo in the USA.",
			"answer": "True",
			"explaination": "Super Mario World and Pilotwings were launch titles for the Super Nintendo in the USA.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"difficulty": 1,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "tf",
			"question": "Super Mario World was a launch title for the NES in the USA.",
			"answer": "False",
			"explaination": "Super Mario World and Pilotwings were launch titles for the Super Nintendo in the USA.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"difficulty": 1,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which of these Pokemon does not have Life Leech?",
			"answer": "A and C",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Dustox",
				"Zubat",
				"Pikachu",
				"Nincada"
			],
			"difficulty": 3,
			"randomize": false,
			"author": "missymousey",
			"tags": [
				"pokemon",
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "In the Witcher which creature does Geralt find hiding in an oven?",
			"answer": "Godling",
			"explaination": "A godling is a child-like humanoid that are relatively not dangerous but do like to play pranks etc. Geralt finds a godling by the name of Sarah hiding in one of the major cities in an abandoned house.",
			"choices": [
				"Banshee",
				"Forktail",
				"Spoontail"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Renegade"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What was the first Grand Theft Auto game to feature a playable female character?",
			"answer": "Grand Theft Auto",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Grand Theft Auto 2",
				"GTA Online",
				"Grand Theft Auto: Chinatown Wars"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "dandyhighwayman84"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "In the Mass Effect franchise what species is fully comprised of women?",
			"answer": "Asari",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Turians",
				"Geth",
				"None of the Above"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Renegade"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "In the Borderlands franchise who made the Crimson Raiders?",
			"answer": "Roland",
			"explaination": "Roland made the Crimson Raiders to rebel against Handsome Jack and the bandit clans of Pandora.",
			"choices": [
				"Boom and Bewm",
				"Captain Flynt",
				"Handsome Jack"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Renegade"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "In Borderlands 3 what is the camp with Roland's memorial called?",
			"answer": "None of the Above",
			"explaination": "Roland's Rest is a camp on Pandora where you can see a memorial dedicated to Roland.",
			"choices": [
				"Roland's Redoubt",
				"Aiur",
				"Crimson Sand",
				"The splinterlands"
			],
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Renegade"
		},
		{
			"type": "tf",
			"question": "In the fallout series deathclaws are a product of radiation.",
			"answer": "False",
			"explaination": "Deathclaws are actually a product of a pre-war project conducted by the U.S Army to be deployed in the battle of Anchorage but never saw battle due to problems with domestication.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"difficulty": 1,
			"author": "Renegade"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "In the fallout series what drug was not made by pre-war scientists?",
			"answer": "Jet",
			"explaination": "Psycho and Daddy-O was made by the U.S military to increase soldiers capabilities on the battlefield and mentats was made by scientists to empower the brains capabilities while jet was made by a mad scientist kid in post-war California.",
			"choices": [
				"Psycho",
				"Mentats",
				"Daddy-O"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Renegade"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which video game featured the first easter egg?",
			"answer": "Adventure",
			"explaination": "If you’ve seen Ready Player One the answer is right there. Adventure was released in 1979 on an Atari game system. The first Easter egg, which was the name of its creator hidden in the game.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"choice_type": "retro_games",
			"author": "Shindesu",
			"tags": [
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Excluding Animal Crossing: New Leaf, who is the Town Mayor throughout the Animal Crossing Series?",
			"answer": "Tortimer",
			"explaination": "Tortimer is the Mayor of your town in each of the Animal Crossing Games leading up to New Leaf.",
			"choices": [
				"Tom Nook",
				"Blathers",
				"Isabelle"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "FancyAlly",
			"tags": [
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Knuckles, a character in the Sonic the Hedgehog Franchise, is what kind of animal?",
			"answer": "Echidna",
			"explaination": "Knuckles is an Echidna, and in the series he has the ability to glide and climb up walls, as well as being a powerful fighter with spiked hands.",
			"choices": [
				"Hedgehog",
				"Porcupine",
				"Platypus"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "FancyAlly"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Tails, a character in the Sonic the Hedgehog Franchise, is what kind of animal?",
			"answer": "None of the Above",
			"explaination": "Tails is a two-tailed fox.",
			"choices": [
				"Hedgehog",
				"Porcupine",
				"Wolf",
				"Jackal"
			],
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Aerfalle"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What is the south-wester part of the map called in Fallout 4?",
			"answer": "The Glowing Sea",
			"explaination": "The glowing sea is the initial drop point for the bombs in the New England area. Explaining the hordes of feral ghouls, radscorpions, and deathclaws from the destroyed military buildings in that area.",
			"choices": [
				"Radiation Sea",
				"The Divide",
				"Crater of Atom"
			],
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Renegade"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Who is the legendary videogame designer who created the Mario franchise?",
			"answer": "Shigeru Miyamoto",
			"explaination": "Shigeru Miyamoto is not only credited with creating the Mario franchise but also \"The Legend of Zelda\", \"Star Fox\" and others. Born in 1952, he now serves as a representative director for Nintendo.",
			"choices": [
				"Hideo Kojima",
				"Todd Howard",
				"Shuntaro Furukawa"
			],
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which of the following has not been the historic setting for an Assassin’s Creed game?",
			"answer": "A and B",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Feudal Japan",
				"Pombaline-era Portugal",
				"Renaissance Italy",
				"Victorian London"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"randomize": false,
			"author": "dandyhighwayman84"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which of the following has not been featured in an elder scrolls title including elder scrolls online?",
			"answer": "Black Marsh",
			"explaination": "In the Elder Scrolls series: Black Marsh, the argonian homeland, has not been featured due to lore reasons since a plague in Black Marsh will kill any race not argonian, which has lead to superstition that the argonians made it as a bioweapon of sorts.",
			"choices": [
				"Morrowind",
				"Cyrodiil",
				"High Rock"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Renegade"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What is the name of the alien alliance who are the main antagonist in the first trilogy of *Halo* games?",
			"answer": "Covenant",
			"explaination": "The Covenant deem it the will of their gods that they destroy the human race.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"choice_type": "factions",
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"halo",
				"xbox"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which of the following is __NOT__ a villain from the Metal Gear Solid franchise?",
			"answer": "Bullet Witch",
			"explaination": "Bullet Witch is an Action Adventure game from 2006. It's name could EASILY be a character from Metal Gear Solid though. Also... the character names in Metal Gear are messed up.",
			"choices": [
				"Laughing Octopus",
				"Night Fright",
				"The Fear"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "JollyStranger"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What was the first video game played in space?",
			"answer": "Tetris",
			"explaination": "Tetris was taken into space in 1993 by cosmonaut Aleksandr Serebrov to the MIR space station",
			"choices": [
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"choice_type": "games",
			"author": "deathsfew",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What is the main characters name in the Zelda series?",
			"answer": "Link",
			"explaination": "Link is the main character. Not Zelda.",
			"choices": [
				"Zelda"
			],
			"difficulty": 1,
			"choice_type": "characters",
			"author": "deathsfew",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What game had a Pandemic named Corrupted Blood that has had an article in a medical journal written about it?",
			"answer": "World of Warcraft",
			"explaination": "In March 2007, Ran D. Balicer, an epidemiologist physician at the Ben-Gurion University of the Negev in Beersheba, Israel, published an article in the journal Epidemiology that described the similarities between this outbreak and the recent SARS and avian influenza outbreaks",
			"choices": [
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"choice_type": "games",
			"author": "deathsfew",
			"tags": [
				"mmorpg",
				"blizzard"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "In which game did Bowser Junior first appear?",
			"answer": "Super Mario Sunshine",
			"choices": [
				"Mario 64",
				"Mario Galaxy",
				"Super Mario World"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "missymousey",
			"tags": [
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What famous organization headquartered in Beverly Hills hosts gaming tournaments, tracks gaming high scores, and is an official records supplier to the Guinness Book of World Records?",
			"answer": "Twin Galaxies",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Supernova",
				"Double Helix",
				"Double Dragon"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "dandyhighwayman84",
			"tags": [
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "How long did it take Markus Persson to create the first version of *Minecraft*?",
			"answer": "One Week",
			"explaination": "Notch released the *alpha version* of *Minecraft* in just 6 Days, with a fully-marketable version coming out two years later.",
			"choices": [
				"One Day",
				"One Month",
				"One Year",
				"One Decade"
			],
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Aerfalle"
		},
		{
			"type": "tf",
			"question": "It took over a year to release the first version of Minecraft.",
			"answer": "False",
			"explaination": "Notch released the *alpha version* of *Minecraft* in just 6 Days, with a fully-marketable version coming out two years later.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"difficulty": 1,
			"author": "Aerfalle"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which game widely popularized the Konami Code?",
			"answer": "Contra",
			"explaination": "The Konami Code was widely popularized due to its inclusion in the NES home version of Contra (1988), where it allowed the player to obtain 30 free lives. Since then the code has become part of popular culture in general, even appearing in many non-Konami games and diverse media, such as clothing, advertisements and non-gaming related software.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"choice_type": "retro_games",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "The PlayStation prototype was designed by Sony in collaboration with which company?",
			"answer": "Nintendo",
			"explaination": "The PlayStation was originally a CD-ROM add-on for the Super Nintendo. Nintendo pulling out of the deal in 1991 prompted Sony to eventually produce it on their own.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"choice_type": "console_companies",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"sony"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which country had banned the sale of the original *Grand Theft Auto*?",
			"answer": "Brazil",
			"explaination": "In 1998 the government of Brazil banned *Grand Theft Auto* (including a $8,500 fine to anyone caught selling it) due to their belief that the game incites violence.",
			"choices": [
				"France",
				"Germany",
				"Britain"
			],
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"sony"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "In what year did Nintendo release its first game console in North America?",
			"answer": "1985",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
			],
			"choice_type": "years",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "The *Kingdom Hearts* videogame series is a collaboration between Disney and what famous gaming company?",
			"answer": "Square Enix",
			"explaination": "*Kingdom Hearts* is a collaboration between Disney and Square Enix. Thus it features characters from the classic Final Fantasy series teaming up with the likes of Scrooge McDuck, Buzz Lightyear and Jack Sparrow.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"choice_type": "gaming_companies",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle"
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What is the name of the last videogame console Sega released in the United States?",
			"answer": "Dreamcast",
			"explaination": "Though released almost 20 years ago in 1999, the Dreamcast was the last home console Sega brought to foreign markets.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"choice_type": "consoles",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"dreamcast"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "tf",
			"question": "Dreamcast was the last videogame console Sega released in the United States.",
			"answer": "True",
			"explaination": "Though released almost 20 years ago in 1999, the Dreamcast was the last home console Sega brought to foreign markets.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"difficulty": 1,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"dreamcast"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "tf",
			"question": "Dreamcast was the last videogame console Nintendo released in the United States.",
			"answer": "False",
			"explaination": "The Dreamcast was the last home console Sega brought to foreign markets. Nintendo is still making consoles!",
			"choices": [
			],
			"difficulty": 1,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"dreamcast"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What game studio, recently acquired by Microsoft, shattered Kickstarter records in 2012 with their campaign to produce a new point-and-click adventure game, arguably legitimizing crowdfunding as a viable funding vehicle for video games?",
			"answer": "Double Fine Productions",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
			],
			"choice_type": "gaming_companies",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "dandyhighwayman84",
			"tags": [
				"microsoft"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "In late 2018, what famous Hollywood actor and singer launched Jablinski Games, a YouTube channel mostly dedicated to video games, pinball, and gaming culture?",
			"answer": "Jack Black",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Jim Carrey",
				"Jared Leto",
				"Bruce Willis"
			],
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "dandyhighwayman84",
			"tags": [
				"culture"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which iconic videogame character originated as a simple placeholder?",
			"answer": "Kirby",
			"explaination": "As can probably be ascertained by his simple appearance, Kirby is the one that was original intended to be a circular placeholder for another character.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"choice_type": "characters",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which videogame holds the record for having the highest budget ever to produce?",
			"answer": "Grand Theft Auto V",
			"explaination": "With an estimated budget of $256 million, *Grand Theft Auto V* cost more to make than many major motion films.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"choice_type": "games",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"culture"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Dr. Light is the creator of which classic videogame character?",
			"answer": "Mega Man",
			"explaination": "Mega Man was created by the fictional Dr. Light, who despite being a pacifist sees the need for force when necessary.",
			"choices": [
			],
			"choice_type": "characters",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What was Nintendo's Most Controversial M rated Video game?",
			"answer": "Conkers Bad Fur Day",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Mortal Kombat",
				"Golden Eye",
				"DOOM"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Tannyerz",
			"tags": [
				"nintendo",
				"culture"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What was the First M Rated Video to be released?",
			"answer": "Mortal Kombat",
			"explaination": "Congressional hearings were held and the Entertainment Software Rating Board (ESRB) was established in 1994, two years after the release of Mortal Kombat. Unsurprisingly, the game was the first to receive the Mature rating.",
			"choices": [
				"Conkers Bad Fur Day",
				"Golden Eye",
				"DOOM"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Tannyerz",
			"tags": [
				"culture"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "In the 1980s, Nintendo named a classic video game character after their attorney. What was that attorney’s name?",
			"answer": "John Kirby",
			"explaination": "In the 1980s, Nintendo named a classic video game character after their attorney, who successfully defended the company against Universal City Studios over the copyrightability of the character of Donkey Kong.",
			"choices": [
				"Doug Bowser",
				"Mario Lawrence",
				"Frank Samus"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "dandyhighwayman84",
			"tags": [
				"nintendo",
				"culture",
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What was Professor Layton's first name?",
			"answer": "Hershel",
			"explaination": "Professor Hershel Layton is the title character and Protagonist of the PROFESSOR LAYTON series of Puzzle detective games for Nintendo DS.",
			"choices": [
				"Nigel",
				"Arthur",
				"Sherlock"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "FancyAlly",
			"tags": [
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What is Baron's full name from League of Legends?",
			"answer": "Baron Nashor",
			"explaination": "In League Of Legends, the strongest team buff can be obtained when your team goes to the jungle and defeats the strongest Neutral Monster, *Baron Nashor*",
			"choices": [
				"Baron Rohshan",
				"Baron Voidor",
				"Baron Urfer"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "FancyAlly",
			"tags": [
				"league of legends",
				"contemporary"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which videogame company originally brought Pac-Man to home consoles?",
			"answer": "Atari",
			"explaination": "Pac-Man was first brought to home consoles via the Atari 2600 way back in 1982.",
			"choices": [
				"Lionhead",
				"Acclaim",
				"Midway"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "In the Pokémon Anime Theme Song, what is the first line in the second verse?",
			"answer": "Every challenge along the way, with courage, I will face.",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Everybody wants to be a master, everybody wants to show their skills.",
				"There's no question, no mystery, I'm much better when you're with me.",
				"I will battle every day, to claim my rightful place."
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "EddieGames",
			"tags": [
				"pokemon"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which theme park was inspired and is heavily influenced by *World of Warcraft* and *StarCraft*?",
			"answer": "World Joyland",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"IMG Worlds of Adventure",
				"Tokyo Disney Resort",
				"Efteling"
			],
			"choice_type": "World Joyland, located in China, is based on *World of Warcraft* and *StarCraft* despite having no formal agreement with its developers, Blizzard Entertainment.",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"blizzard",
				"contemporary"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What was the first videogame system released to be used in conjunction with a television?",
			"answer": "Odyssey",
			"explaination": "The Magnavox Odyssey was first released in 1972, and it is known for featuring a game similar to Pong.",
			"choices": [
				"Intellivision",
				"ColecoVision",
				"Vectrex"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What is the name of the hero from *Mike Tyson's Punch-Out*?",
			"answer": "Little Mac",
			"explaination": "Little Mac is but a wee fighter yet can defeat the one-punch wonder Mike Tyson if the gamer is fast enough.",
			"choices": [
				"Doc Louis",
				"Big Mac",
				"Mr. Dream"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which of these was not a cheat code in Starcraft?",
			"answer": "All your base are belong to us",
			"explaination": "This was a cheat code for warcraft 3 which gave you an immediate victory for the current level. The corresponding cheat in Starcraft was *There is no cow level*",
			"choices": [
				"Black sheep wall ",
				"Power overwhelming",
				"Show me the money"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"author": "Teri",
			"tags": [
				""
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which is the world-famous Konami Code?",
			"answer": "U U D D L R L R B A Start",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"D D U U L R L R B A Start",
				"U U D D L R L R A B Select Start",
				"U U D D R L R L B A Select"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which of these was not an enemy in Mother 2 / Earthbound?",
			"answer": "Mighty Bitey Snake",
			"explaination": "Mighty Bitey Snake was an enemy from Mother 3.",
			"choices": [
				"Unassuming Local Guy",
				"Handsome Tom",
				"Slimy Little Pie"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "vhasr",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What character from Overwatch is friends and partner in the field with Winston?",
			"answer": "Tracer",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"D.VA",
				"Mcree",
				"Reaper"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Fibonacci",
			"tags": [
				"overwatch",
				"blizzard",
				"contemporary"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "The Overwatch Hero Reinhardt is a",
			"answer": "Tank",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Support",
				"Defense",
				"Offense"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"author": "Fibonacci",
			"tags": [
				"overwatch",
				"blizzard",
				"contemporary"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "tf",
			"question": "The Overwatch hero Mercy is a Healer.",
			"answer": "True",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"overwatch",
				"blizzard",
				"contemporary"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "The Overwatch hero Bastion loves",
			"answer": "Birds",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Flowers",
				"Leaves",
				"Trees"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Fibonacci",
			"tags": [
				"overwatch",
				"blizzard",
				"contemporary"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What Animal is Winston from Overwatch?",
			"answer": "Monkey",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Orangutan",
				"Ape",
				"Chimpanzee"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Fibonacci",
			"tags": [
				"overwatch",
				"blizzard",
				"contemporary"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which of the following is __not__ a Magic Spell from the Kingdom Hearts franchise?",
			"answer": "Aquara",
			"explaination": "Cure heals HP, Blizzara is a Level 2 Ice Spell, and Thundaga is a Level 3 Lightning Spell.",
			"choices": [
				"Cure",
				"Blizzara",
				"Thundaga"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "vhasr",
			"tags": [
				""
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "In Phoenix Labs' Dauntless, what is the name of the Blacksmith in Ramsgate?",
			"answer": "Wils Bormen",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Gaius Copperwheel",
				"Janek Zai",
				"Markus Boehr"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "vhasr",
			"tags": [
				"contemporary"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What does the word daedra mean in the elder scrolls franchise?",
			"answer": "Not of our ancestors",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Demon",
				"Enemy",
				"Family"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Renegade",
			"tags": [
				""
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Characters in videogames who cannot be outrightly controlled by players are acronymed as what?",
			"answer": "NPCs",
			"explaination": "Non-playable characters (NPCs) are those that players cannot control, though their actions can be influenced.",
			"choices": [
				"WoWs",
				"CPNs",
				"RPGs"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				""
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "The game PT, released in 2014, was a collaboration between game designer Hideo Kojima and which movie director?",
			"answer": "Guillermo del Toro",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Peter Jackson",
				"Joss Whedon",
				"David Lynch"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Megaman703",
			"tags": [
				""
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "In Super Mario RPG: Legend of the Seven Stars, Geno firsts introduces himself to Mario by what name?",
			"answer": "♡♪!?",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"qXWYpM",
				":)#$&",
				"Geno"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Megaman703",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"nintendo",
				"mario"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which famous fighting game had the working title *Dragon King* at the start of its development?",
			"answer": "Super Smash Bros",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Street Fighter",
				"Soul Blade",
				"Tekken"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Megaman703",
			"tags": [
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Tetris was designed by which Russian programmer?",
			"answer": "Alexey Pajitnov",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Alexi Yashin",
				"Grigori Perelman",
				"Andrei Bely"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Megaman703",
			"tags": [
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "The famous line from Elder Scrolls, \"I used to be an adventurer like you until I took an arrow in the knee\" is a euphemism for what?",
			"answer": "Getting married",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"Getting arrested",
				"Enlisting to an army",
				"Being show by an arrow"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerendyl",
			"tags": [
				""
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "The word *Pokemon* is generally understood to be a translation of which phrase?",
			"answer": "Pocket Monsters",
			"explaination": "*Pokemon* is a stylized contraction of *Pocket Monsters*, which the series was originally called in Japan.",
			"choices": [
				"Catch Them All",
				"Pocket Pokers",
				"Poking Monsters"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"pokemon",
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What is the highest level a player can reach in *Pac-Man*?",
			"answer": "256",
			"explaination": "A glitch in the code of Pac-Man makes passing the 256th level impossible.",
			"choices": [
				"99",
				"999",
				"512"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What is the highest-grossing arcade game of all-time?",
			"answer": "Pac-Man",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
			],
			"choice_type": "retro_games",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"retro",
				"arcade"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What is the name of the circular object that is used to collect Pokémon?",
			"answer": "Poke Ball",
			"explaination": "Poke balls are used to used to catch and store Pokémon to be later traded or used in battle.",
			"choices": [
				"Poke Egg",
				"Poke Trap",
				"Poke Orb"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 1,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"pokemon",
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which popular videogame creatures come from the Howling Abyss?",
			"answer": "Poros",
			"explaination": "The lovable and transformative Poros from *World of Warcraft* originate front the Howling Abyss in Freljord.",
			"choices": [
				"Koopas",
				"Murlocs",
				"Aberrations"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 3,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"wow"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "*V-Bucks* are the in-game currency for which famous videogame franchise?",
			"answer": "Fortnite",
			"explaination": "As of December 2018, players of *Fortnite* collectively spend $200 million on V-Bucks monthly.",
			"choices": [
				"League of Legends",
				"Apex Legends",
				"GTA V"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"contemporary"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What is the name of the primary world upon which the *World of Warcraft* takes place?",
			"answer": "Azeroth",
			"explaination": "Azeroth is the fictional home to humans, trolls, elves, dragons and other warring species.",
			"choices": [
				"Asguard",
				"Hoth",
				"Aiur"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"wow"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "What video game character is often called Zelda; especially by non-fans of the Zelda franchise?",
			"answer": "Link",
			"explaination": "Many people call Link Zelda because that's the name of the game and you play as Link. So they assume your character is Zelda.",
			"choices": [
				"Navi",
				"Ganon",
				"Gandalf"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Unknown",
			"tags": [
				"nintendo"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "*Big Apple! 3:00AM* is a meme and the first level for which video game franchise?",
			"answer": "TMNT: Turtles in Time",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
			],
			"choice_type": "games",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"meme",
				"retro"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which of the following is __not__ a type of weapon in the game Dauntless?",
			"answer": "Charge Blade",
			"explaination": "Charge Blade is from the Monster Hunter Franchise.",
			"choices": [
				"War Pike",
				"Ostian Repeaters",
				"Aether Strikers"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"contemporary"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which of the following is a type of weapon in the game Dauntless?",
			"answer": "Ostian Repeaters",
			"explaination": "Charge Blade, Gunlance, and Heavy Bowgun is from the Monster Hunter Franchise.",
			"choices": [
				"Charge Blade",
				"Gunlance",
				"Heavy Bowgun"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"contemporary"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which of the following is a type of weapon in the Monster Hunter Franchise?",
			"answer": "Charge Blade",
			"explaination": "Ostian Repeaters and Aether Scythe are from the Phoenix Labs game, Dauntless. Aether Scythe is from Final Fantasy XIV.",
			"choices": [
				"Aether Scythe",
				"Ostian Repeaters",
				"Aether Strikers"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"contemporary"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which of the following is __not__ a type of weapon in the Monster Hunter Franchise?",
			"answer": "Ostian Repeaters",
			"explaination": "Ostian Repeaters is from the Phoenix Labs game, Dauntless.",
			"choices": [
				"Charge Blade",
				"Gunlance",
				"Heavy Bowgun"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"contemporary"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Who provides the voice of Pikachu in the 2019 *Pokémon: Detective Pikachu* movie?",
			"answer": "Ryan Reynolds",
			"explaination": "The live-action *Detective Pikachu* is voiced by none other than Ryan Reynolds, who also provided the character's facial movements.",
			"choices": [
				"Adam Sandler",
				"Paul Rudd",
				"Danny DeVito"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"pokemon",
				"movies",
				"culture"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "Which movie did Dwayne *the Rock* Johnson star in that was based on a videogame?",
			"answer": "A and D",
			"explaination": "Though not amongst his best works, the Rock starred in a movie based on the videogame *Doom* in 2005. He also starred in another film based on a videogame, *Rampage*, in 2018.",
			"choices": [
				"Rampage",
				"Assassin's Creed",
				"Central Intelligence",
				"Doom"
			],
			"randomize": false,
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				"movies",
				"culture"
			]
		},
		{
			"type": "mc",
			"question": "IAmDummyQuestion",
			"answer": "DummyAnswer",
			"explaination": "",
			"choices": [
				"ThisIs",
				"TheLast",
				"Question"
			],
			"choice_type": "",
			"difficulty": 2,
			"author": "Aerfalle",
			"tags": [
				""
			]
		}
	]
}